You are who you eat...
Cannibal Taboo is a horror, thriller film directed by Mike Tristano.
Cannibal Taboo tells the story of Janet, a young woman raised in the
wilds of Africa who is rescued by explorer Cliff Hendricks.
When Cliff contracts a rare blood disease, Janet must leave her jungle
ways to care for her husband and their four children.
The bulk of the plot occurs when the youngest son, Paul, is
about to have his twenty-first birthday.
His brother Luke, a successful professor, returns for the celebration.
However, things are not so simple in the Hendricks household, since
fourth sibling Matthew disappeared on his twenty-first.
Moreover, Paul and his sister have an incestuous
relationship, and Janet is harboring a terrible secret.
Janet, played by Ashlie Rhey.
Luke Hendricks, played by Paul Logan.
Rebecca, played by Jessica Simone.
Paul Hendricks, played by Scott Carson.
Cliff Hendricks, played by Joseph Haggerty.
Annie Tramblyn, played by Regina Russell Banali.
Cannibal Holocaust is a 1980 Italian cannibal film directed by
Ruggero Deodato and written by Gianfranco Clerici.
It stars Robert Kerman as Harold Monroe, an anthropologist who leads a rescue team into the Amazon rainforest to
locate a crew of filmmakers that have gone missing while filming a documentary on local cannibal tribes.
Produced as part of the contemporary cannibal trend of Italian exploitation cinema, Cannibal
Holocaust was inspired by Italian media coverage of the Red Brigades' terrorism.
Deodato believed the news reports to be staged, an idea that
became an integral aspect of the film's story.
Additional story elements were also influenced by the Mondo documentaries of Gualtiero Jacopetti, particularly the
presentation of the documentary crew's lost footage, which constitutes approximately half of the film.
The treatment of this footage, which is noted for its visual realism, innovated the found footage style
of filmmaking that was later popularized in American cinema by The Blair Witch Project.
Cannibal Holocaust was filmed primarily on location in the Amazon rainforest of Colombia with a cast of
mostly inexperienced American and Italian actors interacting with actual indigenous peoples.
Cannibal Holocaust achieved notoriety as its graphic
violence aroused a great deal of controversy.
After its premiere in Italy, it was ordered to be seized by a local magistrate.
Deodato, screenwriter Gianfranco Clerici, and producers Francesco Palaggi,
Alda Pia, and Franco Di Nunzio were convicted of obscenity.
The film was released from seizure in 1982.
It was banned in the United Kingdom, Australia, South Africa and several other countries due to
its graphic content, including sexual assault and genuine violence toward animals.
Although some nations have since revoked the ban, it
is still upheld in several countries.
Critical reception of the film is mixed, although
it has received a cult following.
The film's plot and violence have been noted as commentary on journalistic ethics, the exploitation of South American countries, and the difference between Western and non-Western
cultures, yet these interpretations have also been met with criticism, with any perceived subtext deemed hypocritical or insincere due to the film's presentation.
The tone is dark and intense.